Yameen A Merchant

Date of birth: 13th July 1981

Address: 6, A P Trust Building, 53, L J Road, Mahim, Mumbai - 400016

Mobile: 9324273881 E-mail: yams1381@hotmail.com

Personal Profile

Senior Operations, Product Planning & Development and Contracting specialist with over 17 years of experience in Leisure Travel - Outbound Holidays space. Managed teams and handled multiple profiles with passion & enthusiasm, including Branch Coordination, Airline Operations, Strategy & Analytics of data & numbers, Invoicing and System Development.

Achievements

- Received 'Roll of Honour' Distinguished Performance Rating in Thomas Cook India Ltd in 2015-16.
- Received Service Excellence Award Trophy for 'Best Operations Staff' in Thomas Cook India Ltd in 2017-18.

Qualification

Apr 2001 - Mar 2002	Bachelor of Commerce	[M M K College of	
Grade achieved:	First Class	Commerce & Economics]	
Apr 2002 - Sep 2002	IATA Foundation Course Diploma	[Trade Wings Institute of Management - Mumbai]	
Grade achieved:	Distinction	Management - Munioarj	
Sep 2002 - Oct 2002	Sabre GDS Certification	[Trade Wings Institute of Management - Mumbai]	
Grade achieved:	Distinction	Wanagement - Wumbarj	
Feb 2003 - Mar 2003		[Aquired on the Job at 'Galileo Training Centre' - Mumbai]	
Grade achieved:	Distinction	running centre Trumburj	
Feb 2006 - Mar 2006		ired on the Job at 'Amadeus Training Centre' - Mumbai]	
Grade achieved:	Distinction	Training centre - Wumbarj	

Work Experience

Jan 2018 - Jun 2020 General Manager - Leisiure Travel (Outbound) Thomas Cook India Ltd

Team Manager - GIT Holidays Operations, Product Development and Contracting (Managed Pan-India Branch Coordination Team, strategised / brainstormed with Core Team – the Product Launch of Tours / International sporting events, oversaw Costing mastering & ensured correct File Margings on system, liased with Suppliers and various International Tourism Boards for PLBs, Brochure support, worked very closely with Tour Managers Team, explored Tours for new destinations, etc. for the organisation)

Feb 2011 - Dec 2017 Senior Manager - Leisiure Travel (Outbound) Thomas Cook India Ltd

Team Manager - GIT Holidays Operations (Managed Team Operations for tour packages, worked very closely with System Dedevlopment Team - actively involved in system development activities and automation of many functions & reports, updated Costing mastering & worked on File Margings on system, analysed & prepared MIS dashboards, liased with WebTeam for uploading packages on Social Media, represented & received awards for the organisation at various international Meetings/events)

Feb 2010 - Jan 2011 Manager - Leisiure Travel (Outbound) Thomas Cook India Ltd

Team Leader - GIT Airline Operations (Managed Team for Ticket Issuances, Refunds, Invoicing & Credit Notes. Liased / coordinated with BSP & various international airlines for Company Incentives / PLBs. Spearheaded new Air Tickets related MIS / auto reporting system, thereby reducing manual work in the organisation)

Feb 2007 - Jan 2010 Assistant Manager - Leisiure Travel (Outbound) Thomas Cook India Ltd

Team Member - GIT Airline Operations (Executed Ticket Issuances, Refunds, Invoicing & Credit Notes. Actively coordinated with Sales, Finance & other teams, liased with a big Film Production House for Air Ticket issuance of their Film Group to Switzerland in 2008, successfully oversaw the Air Ticket Desk at a big Corporate Group Wedding Function in Jaipur in 2009)

Dec 2002 - Jan 2007 Customer Relationship Executive - Leisiure Travel (Outbound) Thomas Cook India Ltd

Team Member - GIT Holidays Operations (Executed Product Development, Contracting & Operations for tour packages. Was also a part of execution team of Pan-India Branch Coordination)

Skills

Technical: MS Office, GDS - Amadeus, Galileo, Sabre

Interpersonal: Good communication skills, Managing teams

Hobbies & Interests

Reading, Watching Documentaries on Nature & History.

Interested in World events - Sports, Cultural, Adventure & alike.

References

Mr. Samir Kachwala

Associate Vice President - Thomas Cook India Ltd

Mobile: 9820182852

Mr. Yuvaraj Patel

General Manager - Thomas Cook India Ltd

Mobile: 9372700097 / 9892101119